# **Richard Eldridge**

## **SUMMARY:**

Software Developer with 2 years full stack experience. Highly skilled and knowledgeable at scripting, creating high functioning user-interfaces, refactoring inefficient code, and object-oriented-programming due to my experience with numerous API integrations, creating multiple subsystems, and modernizing legacy code. Well-versed in professional communication, troubleshooting complex problems, working with remote team members, and e-commerce business operations.

## **CONTACT:**

Via private message on Linkedin GitHub LinkedIn

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

## **Atlanta Network Technologies (antonline)**

Smyrna, GA | Jun 2022 – current Software Developer I

System Design

• Designed, created, implemented, and maintained sub systems for logistics and marketplace inventory integration. These new subsystems reduced code volume by 60% and increased code readability.

#### Extend Infrastructure

- Created a Linux and PHP solution that maintains data integrity by ensuring scripts run only 1 instance at a time.
- Employed Object-Oriented-Programing (OOP) to unify front and back-end code of internal logistics interfaces which increased readability and decreased code complexity and maintenance time by 80%.
- Designed and implemented an API that allowed JavaScript (JS) to utilize and call PHP classes and functions through the JS Fetch API.

API Integration & Maintenance

• Implemented and updated 3<sup>rd</sup> party API integrations using PHP scripts with OOP and Model-View-Controller (MVC) architecture. This reduced maintenance time by 50% compared to legacy integrations.

Create and Maintain Reports

- Developed a PHP API and new JavaScript architecture which enabled fully reactive reports and reduced required code by 50% compared to previous implementations.
- Improved the user experience of legacy reports by integrating JavaScript and improving their visual appeal.
- Modernized legacy reports by adding MVC and OOP architecture to decrease maintenance by 75% and while improving readability.

**Monitor Logs** 

• Interpreted system logs to identify bugs, ensuring an optimal customer facing experience.

## SGPS ShowRig, Inc.

Norcross, GA | Feb. 2015 - Jun 2020

Department Head of Motor and Power Control

## **SKILLS:**

Languages

JavaScript

Java

PHP CSS /

**HTML** 

Python

## Tools

Linux

Git

Docker

Visual Studio

Code Google

Meet

#### Databases

Percona

MySQL

PostgreSQL

Mongo DB

## Libraries

Node.is

Express.js

React.js

## **ACCOLADES:**

Hack-a-thon Awards

1<sup>st</sup> Place Award- 2022 3<sup>rd</sup> Place Award- 2021

<u>Code Institute Projects</u> with Merit Distinction

Fat Raccoon Website Eldridge Music Emporium

## **EDUCATION:**

**Software Development Diploma** \*EU Accredited RQF Level 5 Diploma

Code Institute May 2020 - Nov. 2021 **Bachelor's of Computer Science** 

Kennesaw State University

\*\*In progress - Senior